# **CLIFTON MATUSZEWSKI**

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

**6**15-796-5865

✓ cliftonmatuszewski@gmail.com

https://github.com/Theskiman

in linkedin.com/in/clifton-matuszewski/

Portfolio Here

## **Personal Profile**

I love to build and create with technology. For 7 years I have enjoyed the hobby of building computers from scratch. I enjoyed the process of putting together a giant puzzle with unique pieces and getting a finished working product. Stepping into the software development industry has allowed me to take this process further, letting me understand the inner workings of computer software. This has given me access to greater and more complex puzzles to build and put together.

Software development has allowed me to take the hobby that I already loved and turn it into a career.

## **Projects**

React Nutshell (2nd Capstone)

The final group project for our Front-End curriculum was to build the Nutshell project again using React this time. Three of my classmates and I created this project using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, Bootstrap, CRUD, JSON-server, HTTP-Server, VSCode, Git, GitHub. This project was an excellent way for me to get more comfortable with React and by the end of it I fell in love with React and its streamlined way of running. I became well acquainted with React by the end and also felt more comfortable with styling

LINK: https://github.com/c31bywheat/by-wheat-nutshell-react

## A Novel Idea

For as long as I can Remember I have always been an avid reader. Over time however I've run into the problem of finding a good book to read. I strove to fix this issue with A Novel Idea. I built using Javascript, React, and ReactStrap letting users search books using the Google Books API letting them see a variety of amazing books based on genre, author, or title.

Link: https://github.com/Theskiman/my-capstone

## **Education**

## **Nashville Software School**

Full Stack Software Developer

Middle Tennessee State University Biology (2016-2018)

# **Work Experience**

#### **Nashville Software School**

Software Developer, February 2019-Present

- Participated in 6 month bootcamp for full stack development
- Implemented dynamic CRUD functionality into applications
- · Developed applications with HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript, and React.JS
- Used local data and external API's to create dynamic single-page web applications
- Learned Bootstrap and Reactstrap styling libraries
- Used technologies such as Grunt and Browserify
- Used Github for both group and solo projects
- · Learned Behavior Driven Development

#### **Group Projects**

Nutshell- React

The final group project for our Front-End curriculum was to build the Nutshell project again using React this time. Three of my classmates and I created this project using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, Bootstrap, CRUD, JSON-server, HTTP-Server, VSCode, Git, GitHub.

This project was an excellent way for me to get more comfortable with React and by the end of it I fell in love with React and its streamlined way of running. I became well acquainted with React by the end and also felt more comfortable with styling. *Project Link: https://github.com/c31-bywheat/by-wheat-nutshell-react* 

## Welcome to Nashville

Created a project with four other people in order to make a travel itinerary for Nashville. This was our second group project that we build at Nashville Software School and we built it using HTML, CSS, Javascript, API fetch calls, Postman, Flexbox, Visual Studio Code, Git, Github, http-server, json-server, and Grunt.

The biggest lessons I learned during this project was how to better communicate with my team as well as how to read through external API documentation in order to use the databases as I would like.

## **Party Fowl**

Server, May 2018-Present

- Greeted and sat guests entering Party Fowl
- Took orders and ran food to guests
- Helped management run shifts and train new employees.

## Fazoli's

Associate (2014-2016)

Food prep and cashier
Associate Manager (2016-2018)

- Ran shifts overseeing staff of up to 10 people.
- · Helped build schedules for associate and management teams.
- Kept up with paperwork for company income and deposits for each week
- · Helped take and order inventory for the store weekly